Okay, so in this video,
we are going to just
introduce the concept of cost management.
Now, cost management then, as I mean
suggests, it's about estimating all of the
costs on your project and coming up with
the budget for the overall project.
And so we need to estimate all of the
costs on our project, cost of all
resources, cost of equipment, supplies,
cost of labour, cost of raw materials,
and plus any additional expenses as well.
So we need to figure out all of these
costs on our project.
And, you know, first, we need to come up
with the costs of individual activities,
individual components of the project,
right before we can aggregate all of the
costs to come up with the overall budget
for the project.
Now, there are four basic categories of
costs that you need to be aware of.
You have direct costs and indirect costs.
You have variable costs and fixed costs.
So direct costs first.
Direct costs, these are
costs that are directly
attributable to your project
as a result of your project.
You have to have these expenses.
So all of the expenses of your resources,
equipment, supplies, raw materials,
team members, labor.
You have to have these expenses.
If you don't have these expenses,
you can't do your project.
If you don't have raw materials,
you have to purchase those raw materials.
If you don't have those raw materials,
you can't do your project.
You need labour on your project.
You need team members to perform the work.
You need to pay those team members.
If you don't have team members,
if you don't hire team members to work on
your project, you won't be able to do your
project.
So direct costs then, these are directly
attributable to your project.
and it's purely and simply as a result of
your project, you have
to have these expenses.
Then you have indirect costs.
And these are generally costs that are
shared amongst different teams,
different business units, different
departments within your organisation.
This will be considered an indirect cost,
such as, for example, overheads,
utilities.
So these are all shared amongst different
teams, amongst different departments.
Then you have variable costs.
Variable costs then, these vary with the
amount of usage, such as, for example,
travel expenses.
That would be a variable cost.
Or you are bringing in some hourly
consultants or hourly labor.
Depending on how many hours they work,
that would be a variable cost.
Then you have fixed costs.
And fixed costs, then these are fixed over
a certain time period.
So, for example, rent, you're paying the
same monthly amount in rent, right?
Or let's say, um, leases, equipment
leases, you're paying the same monthly
amount to lease this equipment,
right?
Or even the same weekly amount.
It doesn't have to be monthly, but we're
paying the same amount
over a certain period.
It could be quarterly, for example.
You're paying the same amount every
quarter.
Also, for example, um, insurance premium.
Again, you're paying the
same monthly amount for
insurance premiums, that
would be considered a fixed cost.
So you can have direct fixed costs,
direct variable costs.
You can have indirect fixed costs,
indirect variable costs.
But the most significant
costs on your project, direct
costs, whatever is a
direct cost to your project.
because those are the most significant
costs, right?
That's a maximum cost that you will have
on your project.
Equipment, supplies, labor.
Labor is a huge expense on any project.
That's going to be the maximum cost on
your project.
So those are going to be the most
significant cost, any direct cost.
Now, also with direct costs, as a project
manager, you have the
most control over direct.
costs.
You don't always have control over
indirect costs.
A lot of times, many organizations,
senior management will
just apportion a part of
the overhead to your project.
You don't always have control over that.
Now obviously that all depends on the
organization and the industry and so and
so forth, but I'm just talking general
terms.
Now, you don't always
have control over that,
but you have more
control over direct costs.
You definitely, definitely have control
over the direct costs.
So you can have direct variable costs,
right?
And direct fixed cost.
So a direct fixed cost, for example,
could be, say, insurance premiums.
You're buying insurance just for this
project, right?
It's purely and simply for this project.
Well, it's a fixed cost.
You're paying the same monthly amount.
But it's a direct cost because it's
specifically for this project.
Or you can have a direct variable cost
such as travel expenses.
We need to travel specifically
for this project, but the
amount of travelling that we
do, it's going to be variable.
We don't know how much it's going to be.
We're not paying the same amount,
same monthly amount, right, to have
enough, as we all know, flights and hotel
costs vary throughout the year.
But these are all different costs,
or these are the four basic categories of
costs that you need to know about, that
you need to be aware of for the PMP exam.
And you need to consider all of these
costs on our project.
So first, as I said earlier,
we first have to figure
out the costs of individual
components on the project.
Once we've figured
out the cost of individual
components, right, so it
could be at an activity level.
It could be a work package level.
But once we know the cost of individual
components, then we can aggregate those.
that can add up all of the costs to come
up with the overall
budget for the project.
And that's really what the whole cost
management knowledge area refers to.